It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Musashi headed to Mt. Unzen where Shiranui Clan's base is told to be at, but he was attacked by Shiranui's Genba.
시라누이 일족의 본거지가 있다고 하는 운젠 산에 향한 무사시는 시라누이의 겐바에게 당했다.
Who rescued Musashi after falling to a valley was Himiko.
골짜기에 떨어진 무사시를 구한 건 히미코였다.
But Musashi has been attacked again by Genba in Jigokudani, and he fells into a crater.
그러나 지고쿠다니에서 또다시 겐바에게 당한 무사시는 발을 헛디뎌 화구에 떨어지고 만다.
Musashi, are you truly dead?!
무사시여, 넌 정말로 죽고 말았는가!
Of Course!
역시 불사신
Musashi is Immortal
무사시이오
Musashi!
무사시!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 님!
Musashi! Answer us if you're alive!
무사시! 살아 있으면 답 정도는 해라!
Musashi died because of me!
나 때문에 무사시가 죽었어!
Don't worry, Senhime. That glutenous Musashi can't possibly die only by this!
걱정 마세요, 센히메 님. 게걸스런 무사시가 이 정도로 죽을 리가 없습니다!
That must be true! There's no way Musashi can die!
그렇지? 무사시가 죽을 리가 없지?
I- it is dangerous to be here. We have to move!
여, 여기에 있는 건 위험합니다. 어서 피난해야!
Senhime, hurry!
센히메 님, 어서!
But, Musashi's still there!
그래도, 무사시가!
Hurry!
어서!
Musashi!
무사시!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 님!
Musashi! Wake up, Musashi!
무사시, 정신 차려, 무사시!
How is he-gowasu? How's Musashi doing?
어떻소. 무사시 군의 상태는.
I did everything I could, but the rest is up to the patient's energy.
가능한 만큼은 전부 하였지만 앞으로는 환자의 기력에 달려 있습니다.
No way! Musashi, I will never forgive you if you die! Were you a liar, after all?!
그런! 무사시, 죽으면 용서 못 해! 뭐야, 거짓말쟁이!
You said we're going to take Shiranui down together! You said you're gonna be a champion in the martial arts competition!
함께 시라누이를 쓰러트리자며! 무예 대회에서 우승하겠다며!
That is not expected from someone who can eat 500 dishes of dangos at once!
단고 500그릇 먹기에 도전한 놈답지 않잖아!
I won't forgive you if you die like this!
이대로 죽으면 용서하지 않을 거야!
I will never forgive you!
절대 용서 못 할 테니까!
Musashi!
무사시!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 님!
Huh? Where am I-dasu?
어? 여긴 대체 어디이오?
Woah, it's a pretty flower field-dasu!
우와, 예쁜 꽃밭이오!
What is that? Huh?
뭣이오? 어라?
Look! The rainbow bridge-dasu!
와! 무지개 다리이오!
Hey, old man! What is this place-dasu?
어라, 할아버지, 여긴 어디이오?
It's obvious that this is the Sanzu River.
여긴 말이다, 삼도내인 게 당연하잖냐.
Sanzu River?! Then does that mean I died-dasu?!
삼도내? 그럼 나 죽고 만 것이오?!
No, you're not completely dead yet, unless you go over that rainbow bridge.
아니, 아직 완전히 죽은 건 아니다. 저 무지개 다리를 건너서 건너편에 가지 않으면.
I see now! By the way, why are you here, old man-dasu?
그런 것이었소. 그런데 할아버지는 왜 이런 곳에 있소?
I used to let people pass this river, but ever since this rainbow bridge was built, I have no job.
난 이 삼도내를 건너게 해 주었지만 이 무지개 다리가 만들어진 덕에 지금은 할 일이 없어졌다.
Musashi!
무사시!
Oh, everyone's calling me-dasu. Then, old man, I'll go back-dasu!
아, 모두가 부르고 있소. 그럼 할아버지, 나 이제 돌아가오!
That's a good smell-dasu!
좋은 냄새가 나오!
Those are dango flowers-dasu! Yeah!
우와, 단고 꽃이오! 이얏호!
He has passed away.
임종입니다.
Musashi!
무사시!
These are great! I guess I can take some time eating-dasu!
이거 맛있소! 느긋히 갈 수 있겠소!
Welcome!
환영합니다!
M- monsters-dasu!
도, 도깨비이오!
We were waiting for you to come.
당신이 오기를 기다리고 있었습니다.
Well, if you're so happy that I'm here, then I'm happy too-dasu!
아니, 그렇게 기뻐해 준다면 나도 기쁘오.
Then let's go.
그럼 가요.
Go, to where-dasu?
간다니 어디에오?
A welcoming party is prepared just for you!
당신을 위해 환영 파티가 준비되어 있어요.
Party?
파티?
But the dangos...!
그래도 단고...!
There will be food that you can eat!
먹을거리도 잔뜩 준비되어 있어요!
Yes! I'll go, I'll go! I will go-dasu!
와, 가오, 가오, 꼭 가오!
What a big room-dasu! Are we having a party here-dasu?
거대한 방이오. 여기서 파티를 하오?
Shh! Silence!
쉿! 조용히!
The King of Hell is coming out!
염라대왕님 나오십니다!
-What? The King of Hell? -Get down!
-어? 염라대왕님? -자세가 높아!
Raise your head.
고개를 들거라.
What?! Shutentiger!
어! 슈텐타이가!
This guy is one of Hanzō's subordinates, who has been taken down by Musashi.
이 자는 이전에 무사시에게 쓰러진 한조의 부하이다.
Onihime!
오니히메!
And this guy used to be one of Hanzō's subordinates, but she died because of Hanzō's betrayal.
그리고 이 자는 한조의 부하였지만 한조의 배신으로 죽고 말았다.
Is Mr. Kojirō living well?
코지로 님은 건강합니까?
Y- yes, he is good-dasu.
예, 예, 건강하오.
But why are you guys here-dasu?!
근데 왜 너희들이 여기에 있소?!
You fool. This is the spiritual world, where dead people come.
바보 자식. 여기는 영계. 죽은 자가 오는 곳이다.
We throw the King of Hell out of his place, and now we're ruling over this place.
염라대왕을 쫒아내고 지금은 우리가 여길 지배하고 있다.
What did you say-dasu?!
뭣이오?!
You fooled me-dasu!
날 속였겠소!
We're sorry.
미안해요.
Musashi, you do not need a trial. You're going to hell.
무사시, 넌 재판 필요 없다. 지옥행이다.
Don't fool around-dasu! I'm going back-dasu!
농담 마시오! 나 돌아가오!
That will not happen. Floor, catch Musashi!
그렇게는 안 된다. 마루여, 무사시를 잡아라!
I'm dead? That's bad joke-dasu!
내가 죽다니 재미 없는 농담이오!
What's this-dasu?!
뭣이오!
There's a hand coming out from the floor-dasu!
마루에서 손이 나왔소!
That was nothing-dasu!
별 것 아니오!
That's cruel-dasu!
그러기 없기오!
Damn! Unhand me! Let me go-dasu!
젠장! 놓아! 놓으시오!
Even that great Musashi can't resist the Register of Hell.
그 대단한 무사시도 염라장부 앞에선 어쩔 수 없구나.
Hey, you people.
어이, 너희.
-Yessir! -Take this guy to hell and punish him by boiling.
-예! -이 놈을 지옥에 데려가서 팽하는 벌에 처해라.
-Did you understand?! -Yessir!
-알겠냐! -예!
Unhand me! Put me down-dasu!
놓아! 놓으시오!
I never did anything wrong-dasu! I don't want to go to hell-dasu!
나, 아무것도 나쁜 짓 한 게 없소! 지옥에 가고 싶지 않소!
-Even though we want to do something for him... -We'll be punished by boiling instead of him if we let him go...
-뭔가 해 주고 싶어도... -놓아주면 우리가 팽당할 테니까...
I don't like this ambiance-dasu...
왠지 싫은 분위기가 되었소.
Stand up promptly!
어이, 냉큼 일어서지 못할까!
What's going on there?
저건 뭘 하는 것이오?
That is Sand Hell; one has to pull that heavy sleigh for eternity.
저건 모래지옥이라는 곳으로 저 무거운 썰매를 영구히 끄는 곳이야.
The one who's pulling right now is the true King of Hell.
지금 썰매를 끌고 있는 자가 원래 염라대왕님이야.
If I didn't doze off and hadn't taken away the Register of Hell, this wouldn't have happened...
앉아 졸아 염라장부를 빼앗기지만 않았으면 이렇게는 안 되었을 것을...
This is one feature of hell, boiling water in cauldron.
이게 지옥의 명물, 가마솥의 끓는물이야.
I- isn't that water too hot-dasu?
조, 조금 온도가 너무 뜨겁지 않소?
Oh, it must be a guest!
어, 손님이냐!
Huh? You must be Goemondo!
어?! 너 고에몬도!
Oh, and you must be Musashi!
오, 그러는 너는 무사시!
Er, this guy also is one of Hanzō's subordinates that Musashi took care of.
아, 이 사내도 무사시한테 당한 한조의 부하이다.
What a destiny! What a fate! I met Musashi at a place like this!
인연이오, 인연이야! 이런 곳에서 무사시하고 만날 줄이야!
I'll pay you back everything you did to me back then!
그 때의 복수를 꽉 해 주겠다!
Err, don't worry, just do whatever you want-dasu.
아, 아니아니, 걱정 말고 맘대로 하시오.
If I fall from a high place like this, I'll die-dasu!
이런 높은 곳에서 떨어지면 죽고 마오!
You fool! You're already dead!
바보 자식! 넌 이미 죽었다!
Moreover, there is a hot water in this cauldron, that will separate your spirit from your body.
게다가 이 가마솥에는 혼을 분리시켜 버리는 뜨거운 물이 들어있으니 말이야.
I- if then, do I not exist both in this and that world-dasu?
그, 그럼 난 이 세상에도 저 세상에도 없는 게 되오?
Yeah!
그려!
Damn, I don't like that-dasu!
젠장, 그건 싫소!
Even if I had to die, I won't move from here-dasu.
나, 죽어도 여기선 안 움직이오.
Again, you're already dead! Know when to give up!
그러니까, 너 이미 죽었다니까. 포기할 줄 모르는 놈이군!
How persistent of you!
에잇, 끈질긴 놈!
How tenacious! How stubborn! A dead person must know to give up!
아, 고집이 세군, 고집이 세! 죽은 자는 포기할 줄 아는 게 중요하다!
No, that's not true...
아니, 그럴 리가...
Tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle...
간질간질간질간질...
No, no, don't do that, please don't do that-dasu, don't-dasu!
안돼안돼, 안 되오, 그러기 없기오, 안 되오!
Stop right there!
에잇, 멈춰라!
Who could it be that asking me to stop?
멈추라고 하시는 그 분은?
Telling my name when I'm being chased is foolish, but nonetheless,
쫓기는 주제에 이름을 대는 것도 어리석지만, 약한 자를 구해, 강한 자를 꺾는 영계의 망나니 이시마츠 님이란
is right here!
바로 이 날 말한다!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
이시마츠 씨!
So, you must be that Ishimatsu messing around recently!
네가 최근 이 주변에서 날뛴다는 이시마츠냐!
You're gonna suffer pain first!
너부터 고통스럽게 만들어 주겠다!
How hot! How burning!
뜨겁구나, 뜨거워!
Mr. Ishimatsu! It's been a while-dasu!
이시마츠 씨! 오랜만이오!
Right!
그려!
(Buddha of Hell: idiom; being helped when one's in dire trouble)
(지옥의 부처: 매우 곤란할 때 도움 받음의 비유)
The Buddha of Hell must be him! What will happen to Musashi, rescued by Ishimatsu?
지옥의 부처라는 것은 이걸 말하는가! 이시마츠에게 구해진 무사시의 운명은 어찌!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
So that's what was going on!
뭐냐, 그랬냐, 그랬어!
I never thought I was going to meet Mr. Ishimatsu at a place like this-dasu!
이야, 나 이런 곳에서 이시마츠 씨하고 만나게 될 거라고는 생각도 못 했소!
Me too! I never thought the best martial artist of Jipangu would be done by a guy like that!
나도 그려. 설마 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 그런 놈한테 당할 거라고는 생각도 안 했다!
Huh?
어?
Show me the abilities of the best of Jipangu!
자, 내게 지팡구 제일의 실력을 보여 주시라!
Well, the problem is...
그, 그게...
What's wrong? You don't have to shy! Or, do you feel like showing off only when there are lots of audiences?
왜 그러냐. 안 부끄러워해도 되잖냐! 아니면 구경꾼이 적으면 할 기분이 안 들더냐?
T- to be honest, I couldn't become the number one martial artist of Jipangu yet-dasu.
사, 사실은, 나, 아직 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되지 못했소.
What?! How dare you forget the promise with me and come to this world without any regret?!
뭐야?! 이 자식, 나하고의 약속을 잊고 잘도 뺀질거리며 이 세상에 왔겠다!
I didn't want to come, too-dasu!
나도 오고 싶지 않았소!
A man must keep his promise even if he dies!
사내는 말이다, 한번 약속하면 죽어도 지키는 것이다.
Here! Become the number one martial artist of Jipangu right now, right here!
자! 지금 당장 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되어라!
No matter what you say, I'm here because I'm already dead-dasu...
그런 소릴 해도 난 이미 죽고 말았소.
No. You still can revive.
아니오, 아직 살아 돌아갈 방법은 있습니다.
Huh? You must be...!
어라?! 당신!
The true King of Hell! Why are you here?
진짜 염라대왕님! 어떻게 여기 있소?
I rescued him before I rescue you!
아까 널 구하기 전에 내가 구해냈어.
So, King of Hell, what is that way to revive this dimwit?
그래서, 염라대왕님, 이 얼간이를 되살릴 방법이란?
One can go back to the human world when there still is body, and get into that body.
네, 육체가 있을 동안 인간계로 돌아가, 몸에 들어가면 됩니다.
Oh, that sounds so easy-dasu!
뭣이오, 그렇게 간단했소!
But you must hurry.
다만 서둘러야만 합니다.
Huh? Mr. Saigo! Mr. Jūbee!
어라? 사이고 씨. 주베 씨.
Even Osenchan! Who's dead-dasu?
오센짱까지! 대체 누가 죽었소?
It's my funeral ceremony-dasu!
내 장례식이오!
If your body gets cremated, then you won't be able to revive anymore. Hurry!
이대로 화장되고 만다면 더는 되살아날 수 없게 됩니다. 자, 어서!
But... I...
그래도, 나...
What are you doing? Hurry up and leave!
뭘 하냐. 어서 가라!
But I cannot let Shuten and Onihime be there-dasu!
그래도, 나, 슈텐하고 오니히메를 저기에 둘 수는 없소!
You numskull! I'll take care of those bastards, so that you can lightheartedly get lost from this place!
이 자슥! 저런 놈들 따위는 내가 착착 썰어 해치워 줄 테니까 넌 어서 꺼져라!
But they have fearful powers-dasu!
그래도, 저 놈들은 무서운 힘을 가지고 있소!
The only reason they can show those powers is because they have my Register of Hell.
놈들이 무서운 힘을 발휘할 수 있는 것은 제 염라장부를 가지고 있기 때문입니다.
Register of Hell?
염라장부?
The Register of Hell is the lawbook of the spiritual world, and it will actualize the order of whoever with that register!
염라장부는 영계의 법률서로, 염라장부를 가진 자의 명령은 어떤 것이라도 실현합니다.
So it'll work out if we take back that Register of Hell-dasu! Alright, I'll rage before I revive-dasu!
그럼 그 염라장부를 되찾으면 되는 것이오! 좋소, 되살기 전에 막 날뛰어 주겠소!
Really, you are excessively credulous!
정말, 너란 놈은 어디까지 성격 좋을 셈이냐?
But I'm the younger brother of Mr. Ishimatsu-dasu! I'm credulous because my brother is so-dasu!
그래도 나, 이시마츠 씨의 아우이오. 성격 좋은 건 형 닮은 것이오!
Err...
그래...
That makes sense!
그것도 그렇네!
Yeah, right-dasu!
그렇소!
Then let's hurry ourselves to the castle of the spiritual world!
그럼 영계성에 서두릅시다!
Full speed to the castle of the spiritual world!
영계성에 전속력!
I'm ruling over the spiritual world, and sent that Musashi to hell! Today's liquor takes better than the usual!
영계를 지배하고 그 무사시도 지옥에 보내고 오늘 술은 언제보다도 맛있구나!
Hmph. Doesn't any liquor taste good to you all the time?
흥, 당신 말야, 술 언제 먹어도 맛있잖아?
That makes sense!
그렇네!
Shuten! Onihime! Get out-dasu!
슈텐! 오니히메! 나오시오!
Musashi! How did you come back?!
무사시! 어떻게 돌아왔냐!
The hero of justice is immortal-dasu! Now, you will give the Register of Hell back to the King of Hell!
정의의 히로는 불멸이오! 자, 순순히 염라장부를 염라대왕님께 돌려주시오!
You shouldn't be impertinent!
에잇, 건방진 소리 마라!
Dear lightening! Make them into ashes!
번개여! 놈들을 잿더미로 만들어 버려라!
I hate fathers and lightnings-dasu!
나, 아버지하고 번개가 싫소!
Those bastards!
저 자식들!
How dare you evade that?!
네이놈! 잘도 피했겠다!
Volcanos! Throw them away!
화산이여! 놈들을 날려버려라!
Niten'ichiryū: Lightening Sword!
이천일류 번개검!
I did it-dasu.
해냈소.
You're cool, Musashi!
이야, 멋지다, 무사시!
You bastards! You won't be forgiven! I'll remove all of you from the spiritual world!
네이놈들, 더는 용서 못 한다! 하나도 안 남기고 영계에서 지워 버리겠다!
I don't like lightening and volcanoes-dasu, but I hate being flat even more-dasu!
나, 번개도 화산도 싫지만 납작해지는 건 더 싫소!
Heya, idiot Shuten!
어이, 바보 슈텐!
Hey, bro, I'm over here! Get me if you can!
자, 형, 여기여! 어디 잡을 수 있으면 잡아 보셔!
Are you trying to make a fool out of me?!
누굴 바보로 아나!
Heya, hey, over here, here!
어이어이, 여기다, 여기!
Hey, you foolish dunces, over here, here!
어이, 아둔패기 머저리, 여기다, 여기!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
이시마츠 씨!
That was close!
위험해, 위험해!
That was so damn close!
분해!
Stop!
멈춰!
We'll be annihilated at this rate.
이대로는 전멸하고 맙니다.
Musashi, while we get attraction from them, you go get the Register of Hell!
무사시, 우리가 이목을 끌 테니까 넌 염라장부를 빼앗아라!
Roger-dasu!
알겠소!
What?!
뭐야?!
Damn, where did they go to?!
젠장, 어딜 간 거야?!
No use hiding. I'll stomp over everywhere!
숨어도 소용 없어. 찾으면 짓밟아 주겠다.
Hey, you giant dolts! Where are you looking at, you squids?!
어이! 귀 얇은 거인들! 어딜 보냐, 이 낙지 놈들!
How dare you treat us like fools?!
이 자식, 누굴 바보로 알고!
Over here! Here!
여기다, 여기!
Hey, I'm here!
어이, 여기여!
Here, here!
여기, 여기!
Turning your head must be difficult!
머리 돌리기도 힘들지?
Again, I'm over here!
아따, 여기라니까!
Here!
여기여!
Heya, hey!
어이어이!
You can't get us!
어딘지 모르겠지?
Hey, over here, hey!
어이, 여기야, 여기!
Hmph. You fool.
흥, 바보 자식.
Ouch!
아야!
What was that for?! That hurt!
뭔 짓이야! 아프잖아!
Well, Musashi was on your foot!
그게 네 발 위에 무사시가...
What?!
뭐야?!
You bastard!
이 자식!
There was no need to pay back!
복수할 필요는 없잖아!
No, there was Ishimatsu!
아니, 거기에 이시마츠가...
Don't try to fool me when it's written on your face!
속보이는 입놀림 하지 마라!
What?! Say that again!
뭐?! 또 말해 봐라!
I found it-dasu! This must be the Register of Hell-dasu!
찾았소! 이거겠소, 염라장부!
That's right! Throw it to here!
맞습니다! 어서 여기에!
Oh no!
저런!
Here it goes-dasu!
가오!
Dear Register of Hell, use your last powers to send Onihime and Shuten into the hell of infinite suffering!
염라장부요, 최후의 힘을 써서 오니히메와 슈텐을 무한지옥에 보내 버려라!
You did it, Musashi! With that kind of guts, you will end up becoming the number one of Jipangu!
해냈구나, 무사시! 그 근성이 있으면 분명 지팡구 제일이 될 거다!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
이시마츠 씨!
Now, Mr. Musashi, hurry up. Your cremation is about to begin on the ground.
자, 무사시 씨, 서두르세요. 지상에서는 당신의 화장이 시작되려 합니다.
Wah! If my body ends up burnt, then I won't be able to revive anymore-dasu!
으악! 몸이 타 버리면 되살아날 수 없게 되어 버리오!
W- what are you doing! Get lost immediately!
뭐, 뭘 하냐! 어서 꺼져라!
G- got it-dasu!
아, 알겠소!
Never come back until you become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 때까지 다시는 돌아오지 마라!
Leave it to me-dasu! I am your younger brother-dasu, Mr. Ishimatsu!
맡겨 두시오! 나, 이시마츠 씨의 아우이오!
His youth is great!
저 자식, 청춘이네!
Time to bid farewell, Musashi.
드디어 작별이네 무사시.
It's the rainbow bridge-dasu!
무지개 다리이오!
Musashi. I will inherit your dreams of becoming the best of martial artists. You may enter Nirvana and rest in peace.
무사시. 네 무예가 제일의 꿈은 내가 확실히 이어받아 주겠다. 넌 성불해라.
I'm back!
돌아왔소!
Welcome back.
아, 돌아왔구나.
Hot!
뜨거!
Musashi! You became a ghost already?! Get lost to Nirvana immediately!
무사시! 그새 둔갑해 나왔구나! 어서 성불해라!
N- no! I really revied-dasu!
아, 아니오! 나 정말 살아 돌아왔소!
That reviving really made me hungry-dasu...
아, 살아 돌아왔더니 배가 고프오.
Hey! Dumplings-dasu!
아! 만두이오!
Good timing!
굿 타이밍!
It's tasty-dasu!
맛있소!
T- that gluttony could be done only if that's truly revived Musashi.
이, 이 게걸스러움은 어딜 봐도 정말 살아 돌아왔다고밖에.
Yes! So tasty!
음, 맛있소!
Musashi had died once. But thanks to the friendship with Ishimatsu, he managed to revive.
한번 죽은 무사시. 그렇지만 이시마츠와의 우정으로 되살아나는 게 가능했다.
To respond to that friendship, go for it, Musashi! Fight, Musashi! Become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
그 우정에 답하기 위해서라도, 힘내라, 무사시! 싸워라, 무사시! 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되어라!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
It is great to be revived-dasu! After eating lots of dangos, I'm so happy-dasu!
살아돌아와 다행이오! 단고도 잔뜩 먹어서 정말 기쁘오!
But those Shiranui bastards came to attack us again-dasu!
그런데 시라누이 놈들, 또 우리한테 덤비러 왔소.
While I've taken them down with Jiraiyan, he's saying that Ms. Himiko is the queen of SHiranui!
지라이얀과 함게 해치웠지만 지라이얀이 히미코 씨가 시라누이의 여왕이라고 하오.
Next story! Mysterious Ms. Himiko
다음 이야기! 비밀의 히미코 씨이오
It's a stormy mudskipper-dasu!
질풍노도의 짱뚱어이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Mysterious
비밀의
Ms. Himiko
히미코 씨이오!
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!